Payal Priyadarshini

Mobile: 07549231832

Email: payal.priyadarshini@gmail.com

Company website: https://sparkwebsolutions.co.uk

My portfolio: www.payalcreations.co.uk

SUMMARY

Full Stack PHP WordPress Developer/freelancer with rich experience and updated skills. Experienced full stack ASP.NET developer in the past but with a gap of about 12 years. Worked in Microsoft technologies such as C#, SQL Server etc. Worked in an Agile environment, has good communication skills and team player. Eligible to work in the U.K.

SKILLS

Updated skills:

Languages: PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery **Database:** MySQL, PhpMyAdmin (GUI), REST API

Tools: WordPress, Responsive Web Design, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, GIMP, Adobe InDesign, Nodejs, Git, GitHub, Bootstrap, SASS, FileZilla, XAMPP, Chrome Dev Tools, IDE –

WebStorm, NetBeans

Packages: npm, WebPack, Browser-Sync, Gulp

Familiar with: Angular, TypeScript, WebGL, Continuous Integration/Delivery, SEO, Accessibility, Website performance, Security, Lazy loading, Latest Trends in Web Designing, Digital Marketing,

Windows Networking, Active Directory & Registry

Previously worked using the following:

Languages: C# (Visual Studio 2003/2005/2008/2010), J2SE (Eclipse), JavaScript, XML, HTML, CSS, Ajax

Databases: Microsoft SQL Server 2000/2005/2008, Data Transformation Service

Tools: NCover, NArrange, NUnit, Reporting Service & Crystal Reports, Visual SourceSafe,

CruiseControl.Net, SharePoint, ReSharper, Team Foundation Server, StyleCop, FxCop, Kentico

CMS

Application Architecture: Design Patterns, Use cases & UML

Familiar with: LINQ to SQL, Entity Framework, MVC

EXPERIENCE

Founder & Owner 6/2021 - Present

Spark Web Solutions (https://sparkwebsolutions.co.uk)

Website Administrator, Volunteering

11/2019 – Present

Cambourne Timebank www.cambournetimebank.org.uk, Cambourne

Volunteering as a Website Administrator for Cambourne Timebank. My responsibilities include to take care of all aspects of the websites, starting from deciding on the Web hosting service, setup the website

from scratch on WordPress, making Logo for Cambourne Timebank, good look and feel of the website and keeping it up to date with all the latest and relevant information. I had also setup SSL for the website.

I also take opportunities in my social network, wherever possible to apply my skills, either by implementation or by providing guidance. Some of these being working for a charities: Assistance in setting up website for Cambourne Electronics & Robotics Club, creation of poster for activities in HSS, consultancy and guidance for website setup of company in India, Prakash Sports.

Web Designer Career Programme Training Dragon, London

4/2018 - 1/2021

This comprehensive course covered the following topics:

HTML5, CSS3, and basic JavaScript, Graphic Design, JavaScript & JQuery, PHP & MySQL, WordPress, Advanced HTML5 & CSS3, Responsive web design, SQL, Bootstrap, NODEJS TOOLS, GITHUB & GIT, SASS

Teaching Assistant

9/2016 - 4/2019

Morley Memorial Primary School, Cambridge.

Since my children were very young, I started looking for some opportunities that would fit well with work and home life balance and decided to pursue job of teaching assistant. I learnt soft skills like team work, discipline, communication, leadership, confidence and a lot of patience. I prepared myself with a 'CACHE Level 3 Diploma in Supporting Teaching and Learning' from TA College and pursued the profession successfully here in UK.

Parental Leave 2010 – 2016

Senior Programmer at ICT Embedded B.V. (now the ICT Group)

2/2008 - 7/2009

- Project Raet Payroll Direct: Team size –10. Raet Payroll Direct was the online solution for salary
 processing for the business community. This application used the Software as a Service (SaaS)
 technology.
 - Converted the application from old WebFocus to ASP.NET. Worked on both front end & back end structure, prepared user documentation, coaching & giving presentations within the team.
- Project HREasy: Team size –10. Raet HR Easy was the online solution for personnel administration
 within organizations concentrating mainly on administrative and operational tasks. This application
 used the old ASP/SaaS technology.
 - Converted the old application built in ASP to ASP.NET, developing Reports Reporting services, Report Viewer, managed front end structure C#. Worked with Master Pages, Web Parts, Multiview and Reflection etc., introduced Agile in the team.
- Project-Journalisation: Team size –3. This application used the old WebFocus/SaaS technology.
 - Managed back end structure, writing test cases for unit tests and testing them with NUnit.

Software Developer at Drie-O Automatisering

4/2006 – 6/2007

- Project Siriusweb, Rabobank Eindhoven: Team size 6. Siriusweb was a workflow management system for Rabobank.
 - Worked on the change-requests for workflow management system, customer information & edossier document, worked with all GUI, business logic and database related issues.
- Project Hobij (hobij.nl): Team size 5. Hobij is an employment agency.
 - Provided implementation (CRUD on SQL Server 2000) using XML and merge fields, Implemented the Job and Candidate part of the web application (C#).
- Standard product for housing agency: Team size 3.
 - Built a housing agency buildings management system (C#) from scratch to end (Full life cycle development) with different login and roles, electronic dossier for different logins, developed reports using crystal reports for an overview of the buildings and rooms etc.

| Language Instructor at Tata Infotech , India | |
|---|-----------------|
| Worked as a faculty member for teaching C, C++ and Java | 7/2003 – 5/2005 |
| EDUCATION | |
| Web Designer Career Programme | Jan 2021 |
| Cache Level 3 Diploma in supporting teaching & learning in Schools | |
| www.tacollege.com | July 2016 |
| B.Tech. Electronics and Telecommunications | 1998 - 2002 |
| North Maharashtra University, Jalgaon, India | |
| Indian School Certificate (Year 12) | 1998 |
| Indian Certificate of Secondary Education | 1995 |

TRAININGS AND CERTIFICATIONS (Before parental leave)

M2734: Updating your Database Development skills to Microsoft SQL Server 2005, Atricon information Services.

FJ-310: Developing Applications for the Java EE Platform, Sun Microsystems.

SL-425: Architecting and Designing J2EE Applications, Sun Microsystems.

70-315: Developing and implementing Web applications with Visual C#.NET and Visual Studio.NET 2003.

70-528: TS Microsoft .NET Framework 2.0 – Web Based Client Development.